[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community
Now, we can use the model.
现在我们可以用这个模型
Use image retrieval
用图像检索的
model with deep features
带有深度特征的模型
to find similar images.
来找到相似的图片
So here we go.
接下来
We're gonna take that model and use it to find similar images.
我们要用这个模型来找相似的图片
So let me go ahead and do exactly that.
那么让我们着手实际操作
So first, remember, let's take a particular image.
首先 我们先找个特别的图片
So let's take and we'll call this cat, you'll see the cat image.
先定义一只猫 你会看到猫的图片
So out of my image training data.
然后在我的训练图片数据里
I'm gonna take the 18th image.
我要选取第18张图片
So this is I'm gonna take the 18th images like this.
通过这样我就可以获取第18张图片了
And just so that you know what it is,
之后你知道要怎么做
I'm gonna do cat['image'].show to actually show that image.
我要调用cat['image']来展示那张图片
And so to show it in the notebook here,
为了在这个notebook窗口展示它
I'm gonna set the canvas target to be the IPython Notebook.
我要把canvas的目标设定为IPython Notebook
So all the things we've been doing so far.
这就是我们一直所做的
So, here we are.
这样就完成了
Here's an image of a cat and it's a tabby.
这里有张关于猫的图片 一只虎斑猫
For those images of the cats it looks, appears a little small but
这些关于猫的图片看起来有点小 但是
it's an image of a cat.
它是一张猫的图片
You can play with it.
你可以展示它
So now we can find the nearest neighbors to this cat.
那么现在我们可以找到与这只猫最紧邻的图片
So, lets go ahead and do that like that.
那么一起来实现它
Now, let's take this image of a cat and just find it's nearest neighbors.
现在 我们先找到这只猫图片的最近邻
So what I can do is take my knn_model and
我现在调出我的knn_model后
query it for the image of the cat.
查询那张猫的图片
And so after a query, you'll see that for this image of cat,
查询过后 你将会看到这张图
the nearest images are image 384, 6910, and so on.
最相近的图片编号是384 6910 等等
And it's a little hard to get those images from the numbers.
通过编号查看图片有些困难
So when we create that, we'll create a helper function together
所以当我们创建它的时候 我们要一起创建辅助函数
that takes those indices and actually shows you those images, so
可以通过那些索引编号来展示对应的图片
we are gonna actually take the opportunity to define a function.
我们要借此机会定义个函数
So, I'm gonna define a new python function and it's gonna
我要定义个新的Python函数而且它
say get_images_ids.
被命名为get_images_ids
So in this reference column here has ids, this one here.
在这个参考列里就有id 就像这个
And then we're gonna get the images back.
之后我们将要取回图像
So let's give it as
那么我们这里填
the output here is going
这里应该填写为
to be the Sorry.
应该是 抱歉
The output here is going to be result of the query.
要填写的应该是查询的结果
So let's call it query_result.
所以我们命名为query_result
And it's a function, so all we're gonna
而且它是个函数 所以我们要
do with the query_result is return image_train.
通过query_result来返回image_train
So I'm gonna take that training data and I'm gonna do
我要用训练数据
an operation called filter_by, which just selects a set of rows of that data.
进行个叫做filtered_by的操作来仅仅选取数据集中一部分行
And I'm gonna select it by the query_result that we just created.
我要通过刚刚创建的query_result来选取
And once I've done that and select by query_result,
当我通过query_result选取了
backs to you a column, and the column here is the reference_label column.
返回的reference_label这一列
Query_result['reference_label'] and
query_result['reference_label']
what we're gonna do is say return all images in the stable
我们要做的是返回这数据集中所有的图片
whose id matches this reference_label column over here, this column.
只要该图片的id在reference_label这一列里
So that's what this helper function is.
这就是辅助函数的样子
So I don't have to type it all the time.
这样我们就不会需要总是输入这段代码
We can go ahead and use it but
我们可以开始使用它 但是
I am gonna do a little bit of experimentation with it.
我想用它做些小实验
So, let's just define this function.
那么让我们定义这个函数
So, we've now defined it.
那么 我们现在已经定义好了
Get images from ids.
通过id获取图像的函数
Actually, that's make more sense, right?
实际上 它更加有意义 不是么?
So let's call it, get_images_from_ids.
让我们调用get_images_from_ids
And so, let's go ahead and do it.
来开始做
So remember, for the cat,
记住 对于猫
we had an image of our cat, so let's just say,
我们已经有了一张猫的图片 所以可以仅仅写
get, let's call it cat_neighbors.
命名为cat_neighbors
And so the cat_neighbors are gonna be,
而后cat_neighbors要被赋值为
let's call this function get_images_from_ids and
来调用函数get_images_from_ids然后
as input, I'm going to take my knn_model and query it with the cat as an input.
我要用knn_model查询cat的结果作为输入值
Okay, so this is the cat neighbors.
好了 这就是变量cat_neighbors了
The images neighbors and now what I can do is just show those images.
也就是图片的近邻 现在 我们可以显示这些图片
So, cat_neighbors['
这样 调用cat_neighbors['
image'].show.
images'].show
So we had to play a little bit for data to see, but this was the nearest cat,
我们已经展示了一些数据 但这次是最近邻的猫
this is the input cat over here and you can see the nearest cats are all cats and
这里的是输入的猫 你可以看到所有最近邻都是猫且
they are all kind of like tabbies.
都是与虎纹猫类似的品种
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community